Finding aid for the Max and Rita Lawrence Architectural Pottery Records, ca. 1950-1994 LSC.1587
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Outreach/Publicity
  - Article The 1969 Design Review,. In: Industrial Design, vol.16 no.10., p.49. Architectural Fiberglass and Group Arcon furniture, designed by Douglas Deeds., 1969 December 1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Article The 1967 Design Review,. In: Industrial Design, vol.14 no.10, p.32 Architectural Fiberglass seating., December 1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Article Six Unlikely Tycoons,. In: Los Angeles, p.30 features story on Rita Lawrence and Max Lawrence and Architectural Pottery., September 1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Article Semi-custom Pottery,. In: Interiors, p.52 about new division of Architectural Pottery, (Pro-Artisan)., December 1966 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Article New Pots from Architectural Pottery,. In: Interiors, p.100 about new line - Pro-Artisan., August 1966 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Article Expanded Showroom for Architectural Pottery,. In: Interiors, p.100 about new showroom facility., November 1964 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Article Planters and Sand Urns of Fiberglass,. In: Interiors, pp.147-148, new division Architecural Fiberglass., April 1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Article Planting Pots,. In: Arts + Architecture, p.22., November 1961 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Article Sensuous Forms and Colorful Glazes Add New Dash to Planters,. In: Interiors, p.108 Article on hand-thrown pottery mentions Architectural Pottery., July 1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Listing Architectural Pottery,. In: Arts + Architecture, p.108 products which have been merit specified for Case Study Houses., May 1961 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Photo essay about Architectural Pottery Production,. Bound photo essay by John Jensen for class project, copy of letter from Rita Lawrence to Jensen's school., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook. Restricted pending conservation. (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook. Restricted pending conservation. (Box 13)
  - Reprints of advertisement from Arts + Architecture. 2 copies., July 1953 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The Offices of the 70s. In: Modern Office Procedures, pp.19-26 photograph of Office Systems desk, p.23., January 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - A Gentle Kind of Genius. 2 copies. In: Los Angeles Times Home Magazine, pp.12-33 article on Rita Lawrence and Architectural Pottery., February 12, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous clippings. Copy of Abitare (special Genoa issue). Sample design magazine. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Sales
  - Procedures
    - Letterhead and invoices. Samples. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Product Research
    - Fiberglass
      - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Tile
      - Tile. Correspondence and notes. David Cressey notes, color texture descriptions, color name development., 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Tile Photographs. Snapshots (w/negatives) and glossy prints of installations: Los Angeles County Museum, Mechanic's Bank, Richmond, California, John Deere Building, Moline, Illinois., 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Tile. Clippings, Indian Hill Ceramics. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Tile. Press Releases. Purchase of Indian Hill Ceramics, poster, price list., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Cressey, David
        - Clippings,. Artist-in-residence brochure, clips from other manufacturers., 1964- (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Memos and correspondence,. Sales and production., 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Catalogs, etc.
    - Earliest. Village Station address. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Pro-Artisan., August 1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Retail Price List., April 1966 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Craftsman One, (and before). Before Artist in Residence and Pro-Artisan Line., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Artist in Residence program., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Sweets, Catalog text., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - General information--Architectural Fiberglass (early). Installation List,. Color and texture samples., August 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Building Products Division--Architectural Fiberglass (early). Brochure (), photos of AF molds used in building Santa Barbara Community College ()., n.d. May 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Work Center System--Architectural Fiberglass (early). Brochures ()., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Seating--Architectural Fiberglass (early). Price list and photos (), various brochures w/photos (no dates), benches brochure (), clipping made into brochure, Salem, Oregon ()., n.d. 1968 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Planters, Receptacles, Sand Urns--Architectural Fiberglass (early). Complete brochure w/cover (), New Ideas brochure (, production schedule (Rita Lawrence notes), various brochures, covers, photos., September 1965 n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Catalog 64,. 3 copies w/color and black and white photos., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Architectural Fiberglass; Planters, Benches, Trash Receptacles, Street Furniture (). 3 copies w/ color and black and white photos., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Pro-Artisan (). 3 copies w/ color and black and white photos., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Architectural Fiberglass, (and after). 3 copies w/ color and black and white photos., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Architectural Fiberglass; Net Price Schedule,. 2 copies, no photos., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Architectural Pottery / Architectural Fiberglass, (and before). 1 copy with photos., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Arcon Furniture / Architectural Fiberglass,. 1 copy w/photographs., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Arcon Textiles, Arcon Furniture, Architectural Furnishings,. Price lists only., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Architectural Furnishings,. Price list only., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Architectural Pottery Samples #102. Color & texture samples from various divisions of Architectural Fiberglass. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Duraclay. 3 black and white brochures for dinnerware (), 3 color brochures for planters (), Catalog 64., n.d. n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Additions; Architectural Pottery,. Supplementary catalog showing reflective glazes., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Catalog 64,. 2 copies, copyright 1971. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Price List. 2 copies., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Arcon Furniture; The Hump System,. 2 copies., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Architectural Pottery; Additions, (and after). 1 copy., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Architectural Furnishings; Fiberglass Planters,. 3 copies., 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Artec Containers; A/F Planters, (and after). 3 copies., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ceramic Surfaces: Terrestra Collection / Architectural and Artec, (and after). Photos, 2 copies Artec and 3 copies Architectural w/ color photos., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Artec Containers; A/P Planters, (and after). 3 copies., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Architectural Pottery; Pro-Artisan. 2 general price lists, 3 Lamp Collection w/photos and price list. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Arcon Furniture, (and after). 3 copies of Public Seating, 3 copies of Lounge Furniture., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Arcon Furniture; Office Systems, (and after). 3 copies Office Systems, 3 copies Thompson R/S, 2 copies Office Systems / Thompson R/S., 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Architectural Pottery; Price List,. 3 copies w/color sample., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Artec Containers; Pro-Artisan Containers. 3 copies. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Graphic Structures. Photos, brochures. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Europe, 3 copies., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Group Arcon Furniture. 2 copies. (Box 14)
    - Mailer #3. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Exhibit of class work,. Group photograph which constitutes the first mailing and offering., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - After 1953 (Village Station), (?). Includes price list., 1954 or 1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - King's Road Address,., 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Kings Road Address,. Includes price list., June 1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Robertson Blvd. Address 1,. Includes price list., March 1961 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Robertson Blvd. Address,., June 1959 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Robertson Blvd. Address,., March 1961 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Catalog., 1964 (circa) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Catalog Photographs
    - Architectural Fiberglass Seating. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Arcon Furniture Seating. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Architecutural Fiberglass Planters. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pro-Artisan Planters. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Architectural Pottery - Other. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Architecural Pottery Planters. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Architectural Pottery Planters (early). (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Original for Planters CB-16, CB-12, CB-18, CB-22, CB-22. (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Original for Planter K-97. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Original for Planter G-99. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Original for Planters C-12, C-18, C-26. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Original for Planters CS-12, CS-27, CS-21. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Original for Planters CB 8-12, CB-8, CB-16-11, CB-12-12, cb-12-7, CB-8-8. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Original for Planters CC-30, CC-19, CC-28, CC-23. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Original for Cylinder photos. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Original for Planter FX-2. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Original for Planter F-508. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Original for planter F-112. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Original for Planter G-25. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Original for Planter E-31. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Original for Planter SW-04. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Original for Planter SW-03. Includes news release. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Original for Planter L-15, L-20. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Original for Planter LL-20. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Chair Height Sandurns SW-02, A-2, A-01, J-22, L-15, AC-17, AX-17, LTW-15. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous. Color transparencies for cylinders, snapshots of various locations (installations?) and products. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Planters. 8 x 10 Negatives. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Production Photos, Photos of plant and workmen. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Showroom Photographs
    - Photographs before Renovation. Snapshots., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Photographs after renovation,. Glossy prints and snapshots., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - After renovation. Negatives only. Filed separately for preservation. See photos in previous boxes., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)